# JEREMY BARBER

Web developer (1+ year) with a background in IT (2 years), sales (2 years) and intelligence operations (3.5 years). Experienced in designing and developing user interfaces, RESTful APIs, databases, and responsive websites. Proven ability to convert requirements into software and improve workflow.

# CONTACT

- ieremydev2020@gmail.com
- **\** 702-569-2155
- Las Vegas, Nevada
- unlimitedcode.dev
- @onlytruejeremy
- in Jeremy Barber

### **SKILLS**

# **Programming**

### **Front End:**

HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, ReactJS, JSON, Formik, Yup

### Middle Tier:

NodeJS, ExpressJS, Joi, JWT, BCRYPT, CORS, Helmet

### **Back End:**

SQL, MongoDB, FireBase

#### IT

#### **Networking**

Configure, support and maintain network infrastructure

### Cybersecurity

Risk management, Threat analysis and prevention, Identity and access management

# Soft Skills

### **Customer Relations**

Communication, CRM Tools, Relationship Building, Sales

# **Analysis**

Research, Critical Thinking, Problem Solving

# **EDUCATION**

- # Security+, CompTIA 2018
- GEOINT Professional Certification, NGA 2018
- Intelligence Operations, Cochise College 2016

# **WORK HISTORY**

Dec 2020 - CurrentV NET, Las Vegas

#### IT Technician

- Diagnosed, troubleshot and resolved a range of software, hardware and connectivity issues. Excelled in inquiring about complications, researching, analyzing and rectifying problems which improved quality of service and reduced client attrition.
- Converted dozens of residents into clients increasing yearly revenue by over \$25,000 within two months.
- Created and managed accounts for clientele ensuring the ability to make payments and file trouble tickets through their online portals.

**1** 01/2020 - 12/2020

# ♥ WebMall, Las Angeles Full Stack Developer

- Designed and developed RESTful services for invoice, discount and order features of the application.
- Built new ReactJS components for customer, vendor and admin-facing pages with role guards and conditional rendering for identity and access management.
- Enhanced security of features using form and data validation in ReactJS and NodeJS respectively, preventing SQL injection attacks.
- Worked alongside other developers in an agile environment to resolve bugs and implement features preventing system-breaking code from entering the repository.
- Increased user experience by implementing Flexbox and media queries that guarantee mobile responsiveness.
- Utilized Git for version control enabling rollbacks in the event erroneous code disrupted performance of the application.

🛗 Jan 2020 - May 2020

American Income

#### **Benefits Advisor**

- Performed outbound calls, met with prospects and converted dozens of residents into clients.
- Increased customer retention by outreaching to previous clientele and reenrolling them into benefit programs.
- Maintained logs of interactions with leads and customers in proprietary CRM.

Mar 2016 - Dec 2019

• U.S. Armv.

#### **GEOINT Analyst**

- Established and encrypted communication channels, resolved connectivity and software issues in RHEL7, Windows and those involving radio devices for which two Army Achievement Medals were received.
- Earned an Army Commendation Medal for optimizing workflow, resolving hardware and software related issues, and assisting countless commanders' decision making through the exploitation of Full Motion Video (FMV).
- Collected over 3000 data points and produced a quantitative and qualitative assessment for a pilot program under the Joint Artificial Intelligence Center (JAIC), used by key decision makers to improve the functionality of AI.
- Created macros in excel that optimized workflow, enabled quick collation of data and analysis, reduced analyst burden and decreased product creation time by over 30%.
- Produced a continuity book with instructional guides for incoming analysts mitigating time spent on-boarding and training personnel by several weeks.